NICOLE GAEHLE

314.630.1591 | St. Louis, MO 63123

www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-gaehle | www.github.com/ngaehle | nicole.gaehle@gmail.com | https://account.servicenow.com/personal-data/11eb87f7c/83f53d888/540637b41/5ed11AJVF/resume.html

Qualification Summary

Over 10 years of eagerness to make a difference in a business environment and 4 years of enthusiasm in a technical environment. Aspired to grow into a ServiceNow Solutions Engineer and further grow into a ServiceNow Solutions Architect. Highly motivated, passionate, confident, flexible, and excellent at critical thinking, creativity, problem solving, collaborating, and organizing. Firm IT believer, a term invented to explain true belief that everyone needs to understand technology in their own terms and needs of the business.

Skills Summary

Competencies: Leadership

Industry Experience: Healthcare, Travel, Information Technology, Retail, Public Sector, Higher Education

- Project management, President and treasurer of student organization, budgeting, balance financial books
- Project coordinator such as coordinated large events and secure funding for several event needs, Decision making competencies and making timely decision based on collected facts, strong organizational skills and detail oriented
- Teamwork and mentorship
- Communication competencies by employing communication strategies such as active listening, written and verbal formats, preparing and delivering presentations

Industry Practices/Frameworks

Agile, Scrum

Business

Quality and customer service

Technical Competencies

- Web and application development
- UI/UX and Front-End Web development
- Cybersecurity Principles
- Infrastructure business intelligence principles by utilizing project management duties in teamwork
- **ServiceNow** practices

Certifications:

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC), ICAgile Certified Professional, ServiceNow Micro-Certification Automated Test Framework, ServiceNow Micro-Certification Flow Designer,

ServiceNow Micro-Certification Agile and Test Management Implementation JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, AWS, Bootstrap, C# .NET-WinForms, Java-Languages:

polymorphism/inheritance, GUI design/implementation, factory patterns, C #

Software/Tools: JIRA, Trello, MS Office, MS Visio, Slack, MS PowerPoint, MS Word, Skype, Zoom,

WordPress, Oracle VirtualBox, ServiceNow, GIT, GitHub, SolarWinds, Mac-Cot Editor, MS Visual Studio Code, NetBeans, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), MS Visual Studio, Point of Sale (POS), Adobe Dreamweaver, ITIL/ITSM, ServiceNow, HRSD, CSM, Salesforce,

NICE

Databases: MySQL, SQL

Operating Systems: Windows OS, MacOS, iOS, Android OS, Ubuntu

Professional Experience

ASM Research

St. Louis, MO (July 2022 - Present)

Participant Service Representative (PSR) – Tier 1

- Utilize Salesforce to log cases, update existing cases as applicable, to record each phone, email, or web chat communication with a customer.
- Offer navigational guidance to assist customers with their online account setup, completing withdrawals/loans, updating beneficiaries, and locating account information.
- Ability to provide effective customer service, adapt to call volume, foster good working relationship & rapport with customers, and work well under pressure while conveying enthusiasm, energy, and sincerity over the phone.
- Use resources in Salesforce to provide unwavering dedication for customer satisfaction and resolving customer concerns to eliminate repeat calls for increased productivity by 90%.
- Serve as a customer service representative to provide account updates in relations to 401K and IRAs such as
 account balances, elections, eligibility for loans/withdrawals, payroll processes, profile updates, and
 investment changes.
- Assist participants in obtaining documents for their plan, death notifications, cancelling transactions, common form requests, and user account support.

SyllogisTeks

St. Louis, MO (February 2022 - April 2022)

Data Analyst at St. Louis Community College

- Understand the various types of the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots.
- Serve as a data analyst to review documentation regarding the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots that was administered to the staff and students.
- Analyze data to help accurately identify the given information for the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots to increase likelihood of receiving a benefit by 60 %.
- Compare data between MS Excel and STLCC Software to validate the records for a staff member or student that submitted records for the COVID-19 immunization shots.

Accenture Federal Services

St. Louis, MO (March 2021 – January 2022)

ServiceNow Developer Analyst (Application Developer)

- Ensure all business and design requirements are met by assessing current state and defining future business solution to increase end user satisfaction by 60% and end user engagement by 80%.
- Employ practical development fixes to preserve a custom application built for Facilities Asset Management (FAM) utilizing Nuvolo.
- Assisted in quality management reviews, aka. User Acceptance Testing (UAT), to ensure the quality of work met the business and design requirements.
- Utilized Software Development Lifecyle (SDLC) for configuration and releases of completed work based on UAT results.
- Demoed work accomplished to ensure it meets the expectations of the end solution.

ServiceNow Developer Analyst (Business Process Architect)

- Design business processes to meet process and functional requirements.
- Establish business process requirements to drive out application requirements to increase end user satisfaction by 40% and end user engagement by 60%.
- Ensure all business and design requirements are met by assessing current state and defining future business solution 75% of the time.

- Conduct research, gather, and synthesize information to ensure stakeholders have a complete understanding of the designs.
- Implement development fixes 25% of the time to preserve the business process such as HR Lifecycle Events (HRSD), IT Service Management (ITSM), and Customer Service Management (CSM).
- Managed the testing process for the Automated Testing Framework (ATF) by ensuring tests completed with 100% accuracy of functionality working accurately.
- Utilize Agile practices in Jira to complete requirements gathering for implementing a technical solution.

SyllogisTeks

St. Louis, MO (October 2021 – December 2021)

Data Analyst at St. Louis Community College

- Understand the various types of the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots.
- Serve as a data analyst to review documentation regarding the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots that was administered to the staff and students.
- Analyze data to help accurately identify the given information for the CDC COVID-19 immunization shots to increase likelihood of receiving a benefit by 60 %.
- Compare data between MS Excel and STLCC Software to validate the records for a staff member or student that submitted records for the COVID-19 immunization shots.

Adaptive Solutions Group

St. Louis, MO (March 2020 – March 2021)

ServiceNow Admin and BA at SSM Health

- Provide general support, administration, and maintenance of the ServiceNow platform and associated applications for configuring and maintaining user/group access, catalog items, and Service Portal.
- Understand and support the various interfaces between the Service Management tool and other enterprise systems (such as Active Directory and Corporate Databases).
- Serve as a business analyst to provide documentation for ServiceNow projects and meetings with stakeholders.
- Generate reports and analyze data to help accurately measure the effectiveness and efficiency of ITIL/ITSM processes to increase end user satisfaction by 20% and end user engagement by 40%.
- Utilize the PPM Module in ServiceNow to manage projects with user stories and tasks.
- Develop clear and concise technical and process documentation, making use of the knowledge base module within ServiceNow.
- Construct a visual dashboard for reporting utilizing key indicators to demonstrate department performance to increase end user satisfaction by 30% and end user engagement by 50%.
- Operate in an Agile format to lead scrum standups daily with developers.

Panera Bread

Sunset Hills, MO (March 2019 – October 2019)

Field Systems Support Analyst

- Provided customer support to store locations, and triage issues to identify root cause and resolution required such as access issues, password resets, or transferring to higher tier support etc.
- Documented detailed descriptions of issues and escalated incoming calls through ServiceNow ticket procedures
- Assist users with issues regarding equipment hardware and software as a first line support
- Monitor and manage ticket queue and following up to ensure ticket resolution
- Trained and educate café managers on their products, technology, hardware, and software
- Collaborated with internal teams to provide a one-time resolution to a café reported issue
- Utilized remote desktop tools such as Dameware, Cisco VPN, and Remote Desktop connections
- Wrote and executed SQL queries using SSMS to gather detailed information from café transactions
- Wrote and executed SQL queries using SSMS to validate database information for food builds
- Wrote and executed SQL queries using SSMS to gather details on technical equipment, and to perform resets to equipment in single-user mode
- Handle additional customer related support and additional duties as requested

University of Missouri – St. Louis

St. Louis, MO (January 2018 – December 2019)

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- Assisted professors with grading assignments throughout the semester
- Deliver assistance to faculty members with laboratory or classroom essentials.
- Coordinated with faculty members on departmental conferences and student hackathons
- Coached students in a 1:1 basis through tutoring on how to successfully complete assignments using MS
 Excel and develop in JavaScript a temperature converter by providing constructive criticism

Ascension Technologies

St. Louis, MO (May 2018 – December 2018)

Alexa Business Analyst Intern

- Discovered opportunities for skill development and presented the team of my findings
- Utilize tools in an Agile format to lead scrum standups on a daily basis and scrum sprints on a weekly basis
- Interpret Alexa data through data mining in MS Excel to identify trends and recognize areas to be reinforced to the community
- Educated the staff and residents in small groups to reinforce how to use Alexa for the skills built specific to the community and conducted interviews of the residents to collect Net Promoter Scores
- Identified, analyzed, and reported opportunities of improvement to Alexa skills already created for the end-user

University of Missouri – St. Louis

St. Louis, MO (January 2017 – July 2018)

Content Manager Intern

- Manage the distribution of content across all channels for the admissions and transfer services department through the UMSL Cascade CMS
- Serve as editor-in-chief by monitoring and analyzing all content to ensure quality, clarity, and consistency
- Collaborated with managers to ensure the validation of all content

Recognitions and Achievements

•	Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)	Scrum Alliance
•	Academic Achievement	St. Louis Community College – Disability Access Office
•	Meritorious Effort	St. Louis Community College – Disability Access Office
•	Dean's List	University of Missouri – St. Louis
•	Fairy Gateway Prototype Application	UMSL Women's Hackathon 2017
•	Deleting Diversity Application Prototype	UMSL Women's Hackathon 2016
•	UMSL Women's Hackathon Website	
•	UI/UX Temperature Converter Application	UMSL Information Systems Class
•	Children's Story Collection Website	UMSL Information Systems Class
•	Children's Story bookstore feature	UMSL Information Systems Class
•	Book Purchase Sales Tax Calculator Application	UMSL Information Systems Class

Education

Personal Webpage

University of Missouri-St. Louis (December 2019)

University of Missouri St. Louis (May 2019)

Certificate in Business Intelligence Infrastructure

Master of Science in Information Systems and Technology

University of Missouri – St. Louis (December 2017)

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems and Minor in Cyber Security

St. Louis Community College – Meramec

Associate of Arts in Business Administration - Management

(May 2014)

Community Outreach

UMSL – IS Department

(August 2015 - May 2019)

- STL Cybersecurity Conference (STL Cybercon) Volunteer
- Information Systems Career Conference Acquainted with rewards platform, proprietary database
- UMSL Day for the Information Systems and Technology departments Volunteer
- UMSL Mentoring organization President

CompTIA AITP – St. Louis Chapter

(June 2018 - April 2019)

Board Member as Meetings Chair

CompTIA AITP – Student Chapter

(May 2017 - May 2018)

UMSL Student Chapter President and Treasurer

UMSL Women's Hackathon

(2016 – Current)

- Organizer duties to maintain the status of the event and build a committee to assist in the logistics of the
 event
- Coordinator responsibilities including securing sponsorship for the needs of the event
- Master of Ceremonies accountabilities for announcing winners and providing certificate of participation
- Mentoring the students to aid in making decisions on how they want to accomplish the end goal
- Participant in creating a prototype application to meet one end goal in a team of four

UMSL Hack (February: 2018 – 2020)

- Participant in creating a website application to meet one end goal in a team of four in 2019 and a team of six in 2020
- Committee Member duties such as promoting the event and identifying the logistics of the event

Green Park Lutheran School

(August 2017 - December 2017)

- Project Manager to develop digital solution to phase out manual process of check in and check out students
- Communicated with the team to ensure all tasks are completed in a timely manner both verbally and written
- Collaborated with team for application testing, delegation of responsibilities based on role, writing business documents, and accountability for tasks completed
- Presented milestones to the business to collaborate on the status of the project

UMSL Office of Transfer Services and Off-Campus Degree Completion

(January 2017 – May 2017)

- Project Manager to create requirements to propose an improved method of using the websites together
- Analyzed the processing pains by gathering requirements and documenting the needs of the business
- Collaborated with the team in writing business documentation and the accountability for teamwork
- Implemented a prototype to propose by gathering requirements and educated the business how to utilize the websites
- Discovered opportunities on how to better promote the programs to the community

Digital Portfolio

<u>UMSL Women's Hackathon Website</u> <u>Children's Story Collection Website Code</u> <u>Calorie Intake Application</u> <u>UI/UX Temperature Converter Code</u> <u>Volun-Tinder Application</u> Nicole Gaehle Personal Webpage